So friends, IIC Lombard has
disclosed its quarter two numbers,
so let's see what's inside the quarter two
numbers. But before that, let me tell
you that the company has also announced a dividend in this quarter. The
company is going to give you a dividend at the rate of ₹ per share,
whose record
date will be October 27, 2027, and the
dividend money will be transferred by the
company to your bank account before November 10, 2023.
So remember, the
company is going to give a dividend of ₹.
October 27 is the record date, and the
dividend money has been credited to your account before November 10.
Now let's see
how the numbers look because the numbers look a
bit mixed. Let's
see what they are. For the database, the company's O is
given in LUX. I will
convert it to CROSS and explain it to you. It will be easy
for you.
Insurance company numbers are a bit complicated, so please pay a little attention and
see
what happened in the previous quarter.  If we
look at the total income, the
company had generated around Rs 4538 crore last year, Rs 4499
crore now, if we look at it now, it has increased to around Rs 5049 crore. If we
talk about year after year, then year after year,
in the
company's revenue, almost you can say that you will see a growth of around 10%. If we go by quarter after quarter, then the growth is around 10% to 12% quarter after quarter. So, quarter after quarter, year after year, the revenue of the company is
seen increasing around 10% to 11%.
Let us see the main income of the company,
which we call gross income, gross
premium income. If we
look at it, then
in the last quarter, the company had
generated around Rs 6662.22 crore last year, Rs 5302 crore now, the
gross income of the company has been seen around Rs 6272 crore, that is,
here we can say that the gross income of the company year after year
You saw a significant increase in it. If we go by
approximate
quarter, then you
saw the company's gross income falling quarter by quarter from the previous quarter. There is a
decline of approximate pass. If we
look at the company's net income, then it has
increased quarter by quarter year by year, but if we
talk about gross income, then it has been
seen falling quarter by quarter and you are seeing it increasing year by year.
Talking about EPS, the company's
EPA (sorry sorry) in the last quarter. If we talk about expenses, then the
company's expenses in the last quarter
were Rs 4206 crores, last year Rs 3900.88 crores. If we
look at it now, the company's expenses are around Rs 4452 crores. So if we
look at the company's expenses, then the company's
expenses are fine, there is not much up or down.
Let's see what the company's net profit comes out to be. If we
talk about the last quarter, then the
company's profit approximates in the last quarter. So if we
look at it year by year, then
you see the company's profit falling year by year,
whereas if we
go by quarter
You can see a significant increase in the company's profit quarter by quarter. There
is a jump of around 45% in the
company's profit quarter by quarter. But
why has the company's profit fallen year after year? Your question should be
why has the company's profit fallen when the company
's revenue is fast, why has the company's profit
fallen. So,
you can say that the only reason for the decline in the company's profit is that
in this quarter the company
incurred more money in the form of provision. If
you look at the data of the previous quarter last year, you will
see that the company used to incur
around Rs 1500 to 2000 crore as provision, sorry, please forgive me,
around Rs 15 to 15 to 17 crore,
but in this quarter the company has
incurred a significant expense in the form of provision, due to which
you can see the company's profit falling.
Let's look at the company's EPS, let's
look at the NPA. If we
talk about EPS, then see,
in the last quarter the company's EPS was around Rs 8
last year.  If we look at it around ₹1,
you can still see the EPS of the company around ₹1.75 paise. If we
talk about gross NPA, then if we look at net NPA,
here the company has not disclosed the section of gross NPA and net
NPA, so I
cannot tell this. So if we
look at it overall, then according to me these numbers have been
given, they do not seem to be some special numbers, they seem to be
average type numbers. Let's see
how the market heads tomorrow. So that's all
for today. If you liked the video, then please like it and also
subscribe to the channel.
Thank you.